how am I taking all this on the road
Bella box Bella box Bella box Bella box
if you say it three times rational IRL
will appear in the
mirror love you dude um he's he's a
little bit of a a grumpy Tech guy that's
fine we need more of them to make things
like Bell box um if you don't know what
bell boox is you know and you're doing
any kind of IRL streaming um you know
eiel sorry for you you definitely need
to figure it out okay um so right now
for live streaming I'm going to tell you
really quickly why I think Bell box is
the best way to go and all the things I
learned over the last two days which are
super duper important for a live
streamer like me who wants to be able to
do streaming from your computer as well
as my you know my backpack that I can
take on single track mountain bike
trails both of which can be done with
bell box um neither of or can which can
be done well with live solo and or with
just a phone so I'm going to justify
that statement so stay tuned if you want
to hear what I mean by that and how I've
set up my rig this is no secret I have
no secrets there are twitch streamers
who keep guarded secrets about their I
streaming rigs because they think
scarcity mentality if everybody else
knows I that's not me I'm going to tell
you everything I do everything I learn
as I go through it so here we go yeah so
um the first thing to know is that you
do not need IR toolkit and you do not
need antis scuff
unless and if you are running your own
system from home if you're already
streaming from home if you're already
live streaming from home like I have
done for more than four years at this
point you don't need it you just don't
need it you can run the same OBS that
you're using right now from home and you
can have Bella box on the road that is
taking care of everything for you let me
tell you why Bell boox is so much better
than all the other options the single
biggest difference is the algorithm the
algorithm in Bell box that that decides
when stuff looks good I'm not telling
you the stream Keys No the the the the
algorithm that decides how good your
connection is how much of a thing you
have and dynamically adjusts even though
I heard yesterday that bit that twitch
has got Dynamic bit rate on the on in
beta that that adjustment for dynamic
bit rate is what saves you if you don't
have that let's say for example that
your bandwidth available at home changed
every day between 500 kilobits per
second to 6,000 right you would have to
sit there and keep changing your OBS if
not your whole stream would drop so Bell
box is the single best solution for
navigating the dynamic bit rate
essentially to keep your stream up and
that that means that your stream is
working no matter what it's working no
matter what um because you have a stable
internet connection where you have your
Tower usually you should have a a wire
attaching that tower computer to the uh
to that because you don't want any
hiccups at all in that connection right
so that that's the number one reason to
do it and then the second biggest reason
is because of the new
rtmp server which has now been it's like
2 years now you can actually put uh you
can set on the Bell box and rtmp source
and then you can have anything anything
in the world that can stream to rtmp
which includes DJI cameras all my DJI
cameras uh the um you know this Mac
right now this stream right now is over
rtmp this Macintosh is streaming to the
Bell box rtmp server and that is being
submitted to the OBS running in my tower
just the same as if I were streaming
directly from the orange Pi which is
running Bell box okay and the reason
that is that exists is because you can
go in and you can change what the source
is you can change the source from uh you
can change the source from you you USB
connected you know webcam or you can CH
change it to encoded which means like
I've got a Sony or something plugged in
that needs HDMI encoding or you can do
rtmp which is DJI or anything the thing
that's so great about doing that is that
if you are okay with changing the
batteries out and your waterproof
cameras you can and you have you you've
addressed the heat issues you can
actually stream in the middle of a
rainstorm and you stream from the the
camera that I'm streaming from right now
and I don't I there's no it's completely
waterproof because it's all I can put
the camera on the back of my dog and as
long as the dog stays within Wi-Fi range
of the rtmp server we're good to go and
now that you can actually use the Wi-Fi
dongle or something to make your bell
box into a point of press
every single device you have is on the
same network you don't have to deal with
the the thing where you have to go look
up the IP addresses of your
Hotpot and the bell box you don't have
to do any of that anymore that's all
taken care of now none of that last
stuff that I said over the last 10
minutes is possible on a live VI solo
period none of it you can't do any of
that on a live VI solo some people would
say and and you know and for and so
let's but let's talk about the other
piece of this right so I struggled
really seriously Yesterday by just
sending this OBS to an SRT relay it was
a bell box relay but to an SRT relay I
made a video about it I thought how cool
I thought it was but the point is that
that SRT relay does not have the
algorithm in it that that the Bell box
does so the Bell box is detecting the
bit rate all the time and adjusting how
much data it
sends if I just stream from my Mac OBS
straight to the SRT relay instead of
through the rtmp point on the Bell box
itself I lose the dynamic bit rate
negotiation so the moral of the story is
when streaming from anything that's
using OBS my laptop um you stream
directly to rtmp on the Bell box and
then you still get high quality video
and everything but you also get the very
very you get the main reason for having
a bell box which is the dynamic bid rate
negotiation
not to mention the possibility that you
could actually have two or three modems
combined right so you can have two or
three modems and so you get all that
bandwidth combined and if you stream to
the rtmp source that bandwidth the
signal that ends up going up to your OBS
Tower in the cloud or in your home lab
that is that is the combined bandwidth
of all of the
modems and my friends I'm I I dare to
say that that is as effective and as
cost effective and generally speaking
more practical than
starlink and probably this is probably
the reason so many people don't use
starlink the the the main reason for not
doing that is just simply bandwidth
constraints in America in in America if
I use 100 gigabytes I I get throttled
there's no there's no such thing as
unlimited bandwidth in America it costs
a lot of money so so that's another
reason to use a Bell box with a bell box
I can Team three mems together and you
know and pay 80 bucks per per Verizon
account maybe combin don't do Watch Fort
I'll do a separate video on that so so
now you've got three of those modems all
at 100 Gund and something gigabytes I
think it is each one and that combined
bandwidth is the total amount of bth you
have and the the the traffic is
distributed over all three of those
modems so your signal is better um you
know if one modem is better than the
other one all of that is factored into
the Bell box and all only thing you have
to do is just point your OBS at the rtmp
server running on your bell box and one
last piece of advice here when when you
want to change so like like right now I
have my pocket 3 pointing out my front
door if I wanted to all I have to do to
change the scene right now is just
change go to go to Clips change the
encoder to be that which is plugged in
right now and I can change to that
camera with just I go a Clips change the
encoder come out a clips and boom I am
streaming from a different source and
nobody has nobody knows the difference
because it's still coming from the same
stream and all I did is change the
encoder source and you could have any
number of of things plugged in in that
way if you had if I wanted to I could
have an HDMI input as well into the Bell
box and that would be a third camera
that all I have to do to change them is
change what my encoder is so this this
kind of flexibility is not possible with
anything but Bell box it's the only way
you can do it and the last thing I'll
end on uh I already made a video about
this but you don't need IRL toolkit and
you don't need Andis scope I think I
said it already but if if you're running
I'm going to switch over from Windows to
Linux because I had a Windows update
that forced a reboot that I would not
have been able to do if I was not home
yesterday but other than that running a
Linux machine in the corner that when
you start it up you know starts up OBS
and then having a VPN so you can connect
in and go go man that stuff that that is
the same exact thing that you would pay
$170 for so why why pay for it when you
can just run it in your lab especially
if youve already got uh the skills to do
that so that that'll be a separate video
uh I'm running the rock ship version I
would never run a Jetson again
no yeah the Jetson is no no good there's
a question on this chat about whether to
run a jesson versus the um uh the the
rock chip versions The Rock chips are
the standard ones now um the orang I
should probably mention the I I guess
I'll do an entire breakdown of my bell
box but um this video has been about
justifying the decision to go with bell
box and now that I know that I can
stream from my Mac I can I literally
yesterday I had a Mac out and I was
walking around over Wii I was walking
around streaming just from the face
cam I I could be in my tent and I could
still stream to the Bell box if I wanted
to boost the antenna sign like good I
don't doesn't need it so that that is
phenomenally awesome because you know
that that is you get all the best parts
of dynamic bit rate and and and bonded
modems uh with also the flexibility of
being able to walk all the way around
all all around so you know and I've got
like 12 hours 12 or 18 hours of battery
on this particular computer and because
it's not trying to to connect to some
Wi-Fi super far away because the point
of presence is right here it doesn't
burn a lot of extra battery same thing
with my phone by the way so my phone my
phone is like absolutely cool it's not
hot in order to watch and monitor the
video and it uses a fraction of the
battery that it used to do because I'm
on I'm on the Bell box Network so the
phone just has to talk to the local
point of presence the local hotspot
which is like 20 feet away so so the the
thing that kills your battery and burns
up all your equipment and overheats
everything is when you have to try to
boost the signal to talk to something
far away the only thing that's getting
hot and getting a signal boost and
something like that are the modems
themselves and you can manage that with
a pan or whatever by putting it or
plugging it straight into your battery I
found out that the new M6 if you plug it
into the battery not not a backup Bas
battery brick but actually into a you
know th000 wat power source it it or 100
wat power source it will actually boost
its signal even morec if you take the
battery out because it's designed to do
that separate video on that so the point
is that the only thing that's getting
hot and boosting signal are your are
your point of presence modems that are
designed to do that versus the the
really crappy you know modem antenna
inside of your phone or the really
crappy modem antenna you know Wi-Fi
antenna inside of your Mac those things
don't have to talk to stuff that's far
away the other day everything was
overheating because I was trying to talk
to a Wi-Fi point of presence that was I
was in the parking lot I was trying to
go through three walls and talk to the
one that was inside of the apartment but
now but now that I'm talking to the
thing that's 2 feet away I don't have
any problem I'm streaming at 6,000
kilobits per second same as if I was at
home so so that that's the end of this
video um if you if you're trying to do
you can save yourself a lot of money by
by getting getting into the Bellas
ecosystem and supporting the open source
that's there some some pieces of it are
proprietary the SRT relay in particular
uh which you can do per pre by the way
there there are ways that set that up
there's actually other videos out there
to show you how to do that so hopefully
this has been helpful to give you a
heads up about that that's probably too
long of a video but whatever